

# **Stephen A Thomas**Front End Web Development

**▼** stephen@sathomas.me

+1 (404) 457-8652

↑ http://jsDataV.is

ngithub.com/sathomas

http://sathomas.me

@stephen\_thomas

## **About Me**

Front end architect with extensive experience in modern web development and a passion for delivering exceptional user experiences with a focus on data visualization. Deep understanding of front end development based on the principles of accessibility, progressive enhancement and responsive design. Very familiar with modern front end frameworks including AngularJS and Vue.js. Introduced and tutored development teams in the adoption of leading front end technologies and testdriven development. Work experience includes startups, large enterprises and service providers, as well as charitable support of non-profit organizations including the Centers for Disease Control and the World Health Organization. Author of multiple books on web technology and frequent speaker at leading industry conferences.

## Skills & Areas of Expertise

JavaScript	•	•	•	•	
HTML5		•	•	•	•
CSS3	•			•	•
D3.js	•	•		•	•
Vue.js	•				
AngularJS	•				0
Responsive Design	•	•			0
Progressive Enhancement	•	•			0
Test Driven Development	•	•			0
Accessibility	•			0	0

## Work Experience

Senior Front End Developer at PrimityBio 2017 - present

Front end development for biotech platform providing advance scientific visualizations and data analysis.

Front End Developer at Intellum 2015 - 2017

Front end development for learning management system and other enterprise applications.

Application Developer at Georgia Tech 2013 - 2015

Web developer in Office of Education Technology developing largescale web platforms for academic research and collaboration.

Web Architect at Dell SecureWorks 2007 - 2013

Responsible for all aspects of front end design and development for web and mobile applications for network security service.

### **Publications**

Data Visualization with JavaScript. No Starch: San Francisco, 2015.

"Simple Responsive Images With CSS Background Images." published 22 July 2013 on *Smashing Magazine*.

"Unit Testing Backbone.js Applications." published 25 February 2013 on JSPRO.com.

"Web-Based Visualization." published 5 November 2012 on UICloud.

"Design and deployment of a blood safety monitoring tool" with A. Osuntogun, J. Pitman, S. Basavaraju, B. Mulenga, and S. Vempala. International Conference on Information and Communication Technologies and Development (ICTD), Doha, 2009.

HTTP Essentials: Protocols for Secure, Scaleable Web Sites. John Wiley & Sons: New York, 2001.

SSL & TLS Essentials: Securing the Web. John Wiley & Sons: New York, 2000.

#### **Education**

Candidate for PhD in Quantitative BioSciences. Georgia Institute of Technology. Atlanta, Georgia (part-time beginning Fall 2016).

Master of Science from School of Electrical Engineering. Georgia Institute of Technology. Atlanta, Georgia. 1994. GPA: 4.0 (A=4).